Brian Miner

React / Next.js Developer

Medellín, Colombia | bminer85@gmail.com | +57 322-509-0179 | www.linkedin.com/in/brian-miner

PROFILE

Seeking opportunities as a React/Next.js web developer after transitioning from a 12-year career in petroleum engineering. I am an extremely disciplined and dedicated developer and have built several full-stack applications utilizing JavaScript / Typescript, React / Next.js, Express.js and Node.js technologies.

SKILLS			
Tailwind CSS / Bootstrap	Express JS		
JavaScript / TypeScript	Node.js		
React.js / Next.js	MongoDB / Firebase		
Context / Redux / Zustand	NextAuth.js / Passport.js		

PROJECTS

Coffee Evaluation App (Express, Node.js, MongoDB)

Built a server-side rendered application used by coffee professionals to evaluate coffees according to the international SCA standards. The app helps companies make Purchasing, QA/QC, and Import/Export decisions by providing visibility and access to data while lowering their carbon footprint by eliminating physical paper forms. User login / authentication is performed with Passport.js and login credentials are salted and hashed using Passport's built-in encryption before being passed to the MongoDB to ensure that user data is protected. The front-end is styled with a combination of plain CSS and Bootstrap and all HTML is rendered from EJS template files.

Trello Clone (React.js / Next.js / Appwrite / ChatGPT-3)

A fully functioning SPA Trello clone with drag and drop task boards. The app uses the streamlined *Zustand* library for state management and data is stored in an *Appwrite Cloud* database. The application is connected to OpenAI API to integrate a simplified *ChatGPT 3-Turbo* summarizing tasks across all task boards.

Netflix Clone (React.js / Firebase / Stripe)

A beautiful Netflix clone built using React components. The application mimics a typical user login experience with the login and authentication as well as data storage handled by *Firebase*. A fully functional *Stripe Payment* portal was added and connected to the "Products" collection in the database to mimic subscription tiers and allow for payment processing.

Teacher Reporting (React.js (Next.js) / MongoDB) - In Progress

End of month reporting is an unstructured and un-standardized process at Profesores Extranjeros making it highly inefficient and leading to highly variable reports from teachers. To solve this issue, I am building a Teacher Portal to facilitate this required reporting. The app will use *NextAuth* authentication and redirect teachers to a dashboard which visualizes their current class schedules, student rosters and submitted reports. From the dashboard teachers will be able to update student lists as well as generate and submit progress reports to the MongoDB database.

Resume Builder (React.js (Next.js) / MongoDB / ChatGPT-3) – In Progress

Writing and maintaining resumes is a tedious task during the job-hunt. This app aims to help users in the creation of their resumes. The app will consist of clean React based front-end components on the left pane and a typical page layout on the right. The page will incorporate a drag and drop board allowing users to effortlessly rearrange sections. Both Grammarly and ChatGPT APIs will be integrated provide suggestions on improving writing and to allow users to use prompts to improve their written styles.

Nutrition & Fitness App (React.js / Next.js / MongoDB) – In Progress

The app is a simple fitness and calorie tracker based on an Excel spreadsheet that I had built which helped me lose over 30 lbs. The app will connect to a MongoDB to access and add food items for calorie and macronutrient tracking. The app will be reactive providing a simple dashboard showing key metrics such as BMR, calories burned, and calories consumed along with macro tracking for ensuring proper Protein, Carb and Fat consumption based on user goals.

COURSES

React – The Complete Guide 2023

Academind – Maximilian Schwarzmüller

Docker Mastery: with Kubernetes + Swarm

Udemy - Bret Fisher (Docker Captain)

MongoDB - Complete Developer's Guide 2023

Academind - Maximilian Schwarzmüller

Complete 2023 Web Development Bootcamp

London's App Brewery – Dr. Angela Yu

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

English Teacher (TEFL)

Mar 2021 – Present

Profesores Extranjeros

Medellín, Colombia

Provide English instruction for corporations & individuals covering a variety of needs from Exam Prep to Client Engagement and Career Advancement

Staff Production Engineer

Dec 2014 – Sep 2020

Chesapeake Energy

Oklahoma City, OK

Worked the HPHT Haynesville Shale where I was responsible for production across the field. During this time I led a multi-disciplinary team to implement an innovative production strategy which accelerated \$4MM in free cash-flow in the fiscal year 2020. Additionally, I developed and implemented several flow assurance and artificial lift optimization models which improved new well IP by 14% and saved \$20K per month in OPEX associated with reduced foamer usage. Aside from the day-to-day engineering I also mentored 5 summer interns guiding their technical projects with 100% receiving full-time offers from the company.

Production Engineer I

Dec 2012 - Dec 2014

BP Amarillo, TX

Monitored and optimized production from 300+ low pressure unconventional wells in the Anadarko Basin. During this time I designed and implemented a plunger-lift optimization model to accurately predict the arrival criteria of plungers which improved out plunger installation success rate by 15% and reduced non-arrivals by 30% resulting in lower improving field cash-flow and reducing OPEX associated with workovers.

EDUCATION

*	University of Oklahoma	May 2013
	Master's Petroleum Engineering	Norman, OK
*	University of Oklahoma	May 2010
	Bachelor's Chemical Engineering	Norman, OK

LANGUAGES

English.......Proficient Conversational

HOBBIES

I am a coffee fanatic and beekeeper. I love coffee and the entire chain from production to retail. I am a certified Q-Grader (coffee evaluation expert) and own a small coffee business in Medellin, Colombia. When I am not coding or seeking new coffees to buy and sell, I spend time baking sourdough bread, tending to my bees and playing rugby.